生活大爆炸
第四季第一集
And now the kung pao chicken.
现在是宫保鸡丁
Smooth.
很顺利啊
And finally,
最后
my moo shu pork.
我的木须肉
Whoo-hoo!
给力!
Oh, there you have it, gentlemen.
菜上齐了  先生们
Our entire dinner unpacked by robot.
整整一桌由机器人上的晚餐
And it only took 28 minutes.
而且只花了28分钟
Impressive, but we must be cautious.
是很不错  但我们必须要小心
- Why?  - Today, it's a Chinese food retrieval robot.
-为什么  -今天机器人来上中国菜
Tomorrow, it travels back in time
明天就穿越回过去
and tries to kill Sarah Connor.
谋杀莎拉·康纳
I don't think that's going to happen, Sheldon.
我可不觉得这会发生  谢尔顿
No one ever does.
确实没发生过
That's why it happens.
所以才会发生
Hey. Is the food here?
嘿  晚餐到了吗
Ooh. What's that?
这是什么
That, dear lady,
亲爱的女士
is the Wolowitz Programmable Hand,
这叫沃罗威茨程控手
designed for extravehicular repairs
专为维修国际空间站
on the International Space Station.
而设计的延伸臂
Ah, cool.
好酷啊
Ask me to pass the soy sauce.
叫我把酱油递给你
Oh, does that come up much on the space station?
空间站里有人用机械手打酱油吗
Mostly with Asian and Jewish astronauts.
通常会是亚裔或犹太航天员
- All right. Pass the soy sauce.  - Coming up.
-好吧  给我酱油  -就来
So how's work?
工作如何
Oh, it's not bad.
还不赖吧
Kind of hungry.
有点饿了
Yeah, we all are.
我们都饿
Just wait.
等等就好
You realize, Penny, that the technology
佩妮  你有想过
that went into this arm will one day make
这机械臂所蕴含的科技会在某天
unskilled food servers such as yourself obsolete.
让你这种没有能力的服务员下岗么
Really?
真的吗
They're going to make a robot that spits on your hamburger?
他们会造往你汉堡上吐口水的机器人吗
I thought you broke up with her.
我以为你跟她分手了
Why is she here?
她为什么在这儿
Okay, here we go.
好了  搞定
Passing the soy sauce.
传递酱油
Put out your hand.
手抬起来
That's amazing.
真不可思议
I wouldn't say amazing.
我可不会说不可思议
At best, it's a modest leap forward
最多不过是比《乡村熊狂欢节》里的
（迪士尼乐园一个用机械动物表演的秀）
from the basic technology that gave us Country Bear Jamboree.
使用的最基本的科技前进了一小步而已
Hey, Sheldon?
嘿  谢尔顿
Yes?
怎么了
Peace?
和平吗
No, not peace.
不  才不是
Hang on.
等着
Does NASA know you're using that thing as a napkin holder?
美国航天局知道你用这个作餐巾纸架吗
You kidding? They still think it's in a secure locker at JPL.
开玩笑  他们以为这个还在JPL的保险柜里呢
（JPL: 喷气推进实验室  美国顶尖机器人实验室）
You stole it?
你偷的
Borrowed.
借的
The trick is to carry it out to your car like you own it.
关键在表现得像把自己的东西带到车上
Excuse me.
不好意思
Amy's at the dry cleaners,
艾米正在干洗店
and she's made a very amusing pun.
然后想到一个很有趣的双关语
"I don't care for perchloroethylene,
"我不喜欢全氯乙烯
and I don't like glycol ether."
不喜欢乙二醇醚"
Get it?
懂了吗
She doesn't like glycol ether.
不喜欢乙二醇醚
Sounds like "either."
听起来就像"亦"
"L-O-L."
"噗-哈-哈"
- Who's Amy?  - His girlfriend.
-艾米是谁  -他女朋友
- Sheldon has a girlfriend?  - She's not my girlfriend.
-谢尔顿有女朋友吗  -她不是我女朋友
- How long has this been going on?  - Four months.
-这事儿多久了  -四个月
She's not my girlfriend.
她不是我女朋友
Are you telling me, for the past four months
你是在说  过去的四个月里
I have been asking you, "What's new?"
我一直在问你  "有新鲜事吗"
and you never thought to go with,
你居然从来没想过说
"Sheldon has a girlfriend"?
"谢尔顿有女朋友"吗
She's not my girlfriend.
她不是我女朋友
Ah... d-d-d-d...
啊  等等等等
How did they meet?
他们怎么认识的
Raj and I entered Sheldon's information on a dating site,
拉杰和我把谢尔顿的信息发到交友网站上
and it spit out Amy Farrah Fowler.
网站速配了艾米·菲拉·福勒
Oh, my God! Sheldon and Amy.
天哪  谢尔顿和艾米
Or, as we call them, "Shamy."
或者像我们所说"谢米"
Shamy.
谢米
I am so digging the Shamy.
我必须好好八一八谢米了
All right, everyone pay attention.
好吧  各单位注意
Yes, I have a friend named Amy Farrah Fowler.
没错  我是有个朋友叫艾米·菲拉·福勒
Yes, she is female.
没错  她是女性
Yes, we communicate on a daily basis,
没错  我们每天交流
but no, she is not my girlfriend.
但是  她不是我女朋友
Okay, well, what do you communicate about?
好吧  那你们交流都说什么
Well, my work in physics, her work in neurobiology,
我的物理工作和她的神经生物学工作
and most recently, the possibility of our having a child together.
最新话题是论我们生个孩子的可能性
Thank you.
谢谢
Wait a minute-- a child?
等等  要孩子
You never see this girl.
你从没见过这女的
You just e-mail and text and Twitter.
只有电邮短信和推特联系
Now you're considering having a baby?
然后现在就考虑要孩子了
Amy pointed out that between the two of us,
艾米指出通过我俩的结合
our genetic material has the potential
我们的基因将会有机会
of producing the first in a line
制造出前所未有的
of intellectually superior, benign overlords
智力超群  仁慈善良的君主
to guide humanity to a brighter tomorrow.
带领人类走向光明未来
I'm guessing that future historians
我猜想未来的历史学家
will condemn us for not taking this opportunity to kill Sheldon.
将会谴责我们不趁这机会杀了谢尔顿
Okay, I have a question.
好吧  我有个问题
Yes, Penny.
请说  佩妮
You don't even like people touching you.
你不喜欢别人碰你
How are you going to have sex?
你们怎么做爱呢
Why on earth would we have sex?
我们干嘛要做爱
Oh, honey, did your mom not have the talk with you?
亲爱的  你的私处开始发育的时候
You know, when your private parts started growing?
你妈妈没跟你谈过吗
I'm quite aware of the way humans usually reproduce,
我很清楚人类繁殖的方式
Which is messy, unsanitary,
既脏乱又不卫生
And based on living next to you for three years,
而且跟你做了三年邻居
Involves loud and unnecessary appeals to a deity.
听了太多不必要又响亮的呼唤神
Oh, God.
天呐
Yes, exactly.
对  就是这句
Consequently, if Amy and I choose
因此  如果艾米和我
to bring new life into this world,
选择让一个新生命降临
It will be accomplished clinically,
我们会让生育专家
with fertility experts in a lab with petri dishes.
在实验室用培养皿受精
Which reminds me--
这倒提醒我
you have broad hips and a certain corn-fed vigor.
你不仅屁股大  而且头脑简单  精力充沛
Is your womb available for rental?
你的子宫可以代孕吗
Still digging the Shamy?
还想深入八一八谢米恋吗
Look, Sheldon,
谢尔顿
before you race off to the fertility clinic,
先别急着选孕育科
you might want to think about--
你也可以考虑
uh, gee, I don't know--
老天  怎么说呢
maybe actually spending some time with her.
切实地花点时间陪她
- You mean dating?  - Yeah.
-你是说约会  -没错
- I can't date Amy.  - Why not?
-我不能和艾米约会  -为什么
She's not my girlfriend.
她不是我女朋友
Okay, look, don't think of it as dating a girlfriend.
不要把它当成和女朋友约会
Think of it as, uh...
把它当成
Getting to know the future mother of your child.
了解你孩子的未来妈妈
I hadn't considered that.
我还真没想到
I suppose she will have to have access to our progeny.
她将来应该会接触我们的后代
And you don't think I can achieve
你觉得通过短信息
the required intimacy via text messaging?
我无法达到必要的亲密吗
Probably not.
应该不能
It would appear as if the phone companies have been lying to me.
看来电话公司一直在骗我
Penny.
佩妮
Penny. Penny.
佩妮  佩妮
You do realize I stand on the other side of the door
你应该知道我站在门的另一边
waiting for you to finish knocking three times.
等你敲完三次门吧
I know. I can see the shadow of your feet under the door.
我知道  我能从门缝看到脚的影子
Yeah, my point is it's a waste of time.
重点是敲三次很浪费时间
If you're looking for an example
如果你想找个
of a waste of time, I would refer you
浪费时间的例子
to the conversation we're having right now.
我们现在的话题就很浪费时间
What do you want?
你有事吗
I've decided to take your advice and have arranged
我决定了接受你的建议
to go on a date with Amy Farrah Fowler.
还安排了跟艾米约会
Oh, that's great.
那太好了
- Have fun.  - Wait.
-玩得开心  -等等
You have to drive me.
你要载我去
- What?  - You know I don't drive.
-什么  -你知道我不开车
- Well, go ask Leonard.  - I did.
-去问莱纳德  -问了
He said-- and I quote-- "Ask Penny.
他说  我复述  问问佩妮
It was her cockamamy idea."
那是她的可笑主意
Leonard said "cockamamy"?
莱纳德说"可笑"?
Actually, I'm paraphrasing.
好吧  那是我说的
Having been raised in a Christian household,
在基督教家庭长大
I'm uncomfortable with the language he used.
我实在不习惯他的用语
And to be honest,
老实说
I'm not entirely comfortable with "cockamamy."
其实我也不喜欢"可笑"这个词
Okay, fine. When's the date?
好吧  什么时候约会
- Now.  - Now?
-现在  -现在?
Hurry. We're going to be late.
快点  我们要迟到了
Sheldon, did it ever occur to you
谢尔顿  你有没有想过
that I might have other plans?
我可能有别的事要忙吗
I'm sorry.
对不起
Do you have other plans?
你有别的事忙吗
Well, no, not per se, but...
倒是没有  不过
So this conversation is as pointless
这么说这个话题
as your door-knocking soliloquy?
跟你的敲门独白一样没意义咯
Let me get my... cockamamy keys.
我去拿我的可笑钥匙
Oh, God, that feels so good.
天呐  太爽了
Yeah, that's the spot.
对  就是那里
Oh, baby.
宝贝儿
Howard, dinner's ready!
霍华德  吃饭啦
I'll eat later.
我一会再吃
I'm busy!
现在很忙
Oh, yeah.
爽啊
Just like a real hand.
就跟人手一样
Thank you for driving me.
谢谢你载我去
You're welcome.
不客气
I wish you weren't wearing flip-flops.
但我希望你不穿人字拖
It's dangerous to drive in flip-flops.
穿人字拖开车很危险
- Sheldon.  - Sorry.
-谢尔顿  -对不起
I just don't want to be yet another flip-flop fatality.
我只是不想成为另一个人字拖的受害者
Can I ask you a question?
我能问个问题吗
Given your community college education,
鉴于你的社区大学学历
I encourage you to ask me as many as possible.
我鼓励你尽量多问
Yeah. Well, my question is--
好  我的问题是
and I'm pretty sure I know the answer--
其实我很清楚答案
Is this your first date?
这是你第一次约会吗
That depends.
那得看情况
Does square-dancing with my sister
跟我妹在国庆日
at a Teens for Jesus Fourth of July Hoedown
青年敬耶稣方块舞会上
count as a date?
跳舞算吗
No.
不算
Then, this is my first date.
那这是我第一次约会
Okay. Well, then, there's a couple of things
那有几件事
you should probably know.
你应该要知道
I have a master's degree and two doctorates.
我有一个硕士学位和两个博士学位
The things I should know, I do know.
我应该知道的事  我都知道
My point is, I know more about dating than you,
我的意思是  我比你更清楚约会
and if you were as smart as you think you are,
而且如果你真有你认为的那么聪明
you would listen to me.
你就会听我的话
If you know so much, how come I have a date tonight
如果你是约会专家  那怎么我今晚有约会
and you have nothing better to do than drive me to it?
而你只能当我的司机呢
Fair point.
说得好
You know, there's something I've always wondered about Aquaman.
《水行侠》的有些问题我想不明白
- Yeah?  - Where does he poop?
-什么  -他去哪便便
What?
什么
What would a toilet look like in Atlantis?
亚特兰蒂斯的马桶长什么样
How would you flush it?
你怎么冲掉呢
And when you did flush it, where would the poop go?
就算你冲掉了  便便又能冲去哪呢
Hold that thought.
一会儿再讨论
Hey, Howard. What's going on?
喂  霍华德  怎么了
What...
啥
Hold on. Howard, Howard, slow down.
等等  霍华德  慢点说
The robot hand is stuck on your what?
机械手卡在你的什么上了
You're not going to believe this.
说出来肯定吓你一跳
So, um, Amy, Sheldon tells me
艾米  听谢尔顿说
you're a neuro... something-or-other.
你是一个神经...什么来着
Neurobiologist.
是神经生物学家
Your "check engine" light is on.
你车的"检查引擎"灯亮了
Yeah, it's okay.
噢  不管它
But the light indicates...
但如果灯亮了就说明...
Don't bother.
不用费心了
I've wasted many an hour
我已经浪费太多时间
tilting at that particular windmill.
攻击这座顽固的风车了
Uh, what is that scent you're wearing?
你用的什么香水吗
It smells great.
真好闻
Dandruff shampoo.
去屑洗发水
I have dry scalp.
我头皮干燥
Well, your hair looks very nice.
你发质看着很好呀
Are you a homosexual?
你是同性恋么
No, no, I'm just giving you a compliment.
当然不  我只是赞美你而已
Would have been more flattered if you were a homosexual.
要你是同性恋  赞美不听着更由衷吗
Guys, how 'bout some music?
那啥  来点音乐怎样
Oh, no, I wouldn't care for that.
哦不  我可不想要
Amy?
艾米  你呢
No, thank you.
我也是  谢了
Okay.
好吧
Uncomfortable silence it is.
那就诡异地沉默着吧
Hey, Sheldon, have you told Amy
谢尔顿  你有没有告诉艾米
what it was like for you growing up in Texas?
你小时候在德州长大的经历
No.
没有
Well, why don't you tell her?
哎  为什么不告诉她
All right.
好吧
It was hell.
痛苦得要死
Any follow up, Amy?
艾米  有什么想法么
No.
没有
I myself grew up in Nebraska.
我在内布拉斯加州长大
Small town outside of Omaha.
奥马哈郊外的一个小镇
Nice place, mostly family farms, a few meth labs.
很好的地方  大多是家庭农场  还有些制毒窝点
I'm sorry, how is this better than uncomfortable silence?
不好意思  这样还不如诡异地沉默呢
I don't know. I was just trying something.
我也不知道  不过是试着找点话题
Muggles.
麻瓜一个[此处引用《哈利波特》里的说法]
You slipped and fell into a robot hand?
你是滑倒摔进机械手里的吗
Yes.
对
Penis first?
鸡鸡先着地
Yes. Now, help me!
对  快帮我
I'd suggest a lubricant, but I have a feeling
我本来想建议用润滑剂
you fell on some of that as well.
但我想其实你已经栽在润滑剂里了
Not funny, Leonard.
不好笑  莱纳德
Really? A robot hand's got a death grip on your junk, dude.
是吗  一个机械手卡在你小弟弟上
That's funny, ask anyone.
这还不好笑吗  不信你问别人
Plea-- before my mother walks in, get this off me!
拜托  趁我妈还没进来  快把这玩意弄掉
Okay, let's see.
唔  我看看
No, no! Don't touch.
别  别碰电脑
The program is paused.
程序暂停了
Well, then let's un-pause it.
那就重新启动呗
No, no! I loaded the wrong program.
别  导入错误的程序
The hand thinks it's holding a screwdriver in outer space.
这玩意以为自己在外太空握着把螺丝刀呢
If you continue the program, it's gonna start twisting.
要是程序继续  它就要开始扭了
A-All right.
好吧
Um, how about this.
这样如何
When-when Winnie the Pooh got his head stuck
小熊维尼的脑袋卡在蜂蜜树上时
in the honey tree, his friends all grabbed onto him
他的伙伴们就会上去拉住他
and pulled and pulled.
然后往外拔啊拔啊拔
You do what you want,
你爱咋咋地
I'm not touching another man's honey tree.
我可不想碰其他男人的"蜂蜜树"
All right, uh, forget pulling.
好吧  不拔了
How about we get an electric saw and cut it off?
那就找把电锯  直接锯掉
What?! No saws!
啥  不准用电锯
One circumcision was enough.
一个包皮环切还不够吗
How about an acetylene torch?
那乙快焊炬呢
Okay, I can't believe this needs to be said out loud.
好吧  不敢相信我还要声明这些
No pulling, no saws, no torches.
不准拔  不准用电锯和焊炬
Well, then what do you want us to do?
那你要我们做啥
Howard, I made cookies for you
霍华德  我做了饼干
and your little friends!
给你和你的小伙伴
That's great, Mom, thanks!
好极了  老妈  多谢
I'll bring them up with some Hawaiian Punch!
我送上来  再带点夏威夷宾治酒
Don't come up here!
别上来
Why not?! Are you ashamed of your mother?!
干嘛  看不起你妈吗
Yes, but that's not the point!
话是没错  但这不是关键
Get me out of here.
快帮帮忙
You have any ideas, Raj?
你有想法吗  拉杰
Right now, all I can think about is cookies and Hawaiian Punch.
现在啊  我满脑子都是饼干和夏威夷宾治酒
Hey, here's another possible topic of conversation.
好吧  换个话题
This is a big night for Sheldon.
今晚是谢尔顿的盛大之夜啊
Right, Sheldon?
是吧  谢尔顿
Big night?
盛大
The winter solstice is a big night.
冬至日的夜晚才叫大
It's over 14 hours
在南加利福尼亚
in Southern California.
一共有整整14小时呢
That's an amusing factoid.
这句话仿得真有意思
Thank you.
谢谢
No, no.
不
My point is, uh, tonight is Sheldon's first official date.
我是说  今晚是谢尔顿第一次正式约会
Discuss.
你们继续吧
Is this true?
真的吗
Apparently, a semi-incestuous Teens for Jesus
当然  在国庆日上的青年敬基督
Fourth of July Hoedown didn't count.
方块舞会上的那次半乱伦约会不算
So, um, Amy, what about you?
艾米  那你呢
Do you date much?
你约会过吗
Once a year.
一年一次
It's a deal I made with my mother
我和我妈说好了
in exchange for her silence on the matter,
这样她就不唠叨这事
as well as the occasional use of her George Foreman Grill
还可以偶尔用她的乔治·富曼烤架
that seals in the flavor without the fat.
锁住美味  没有脂肪
How about you, Penny?
你呢  佩妮
Do you go on many dates?
你约会过很多次吗
Uh, yeah, I wouldn't say many.
其实也没有很多次啦
A few.
有几个吧
What's...?
这算啥表情
Your characterization of approximately 171 different men as "A few."
你把约171个不同男人描述为"有几个"
What...
什么
Where did you get 171 men?
你怎么算的171个
Simple extrapolation.
简单的推断
In the three years that I've known you,
我认识你的这三年来
you were single for two.
你有两年是单身
During that time, I saw 17 different suitors.
在那两年里  你跟17名追求者约会过
If we work backwards, correcting for observation bias
往前倒推的话  请纠正如果观察有误
and postulate an initial dating age of 15
并假设你初次约会年龄为15岁
Whoa, wait, wait, wait.
等等  等等
I did not start dating at 15.
我才不是15岁开始约会的
I'm sorry. Sixteen?
抱歉  十六岁
Fourteen.
十四
My mistake.
我的错
Now, assuming the left side of a bell curve peaking around the present,
假设钟形曲线的左半部分在目前达到峰值
that would bring the total up to 193 men.
那就是说总数为193人
Plus or minus eight men.
正负8人
Remarkable.
太厉害了
Did you have sexual intercourse with all of these men?
你跟这些人都有过性关系吗
No.
没有
Although that number would be fairly easy to calculate.
这个数字要算的话也相当简单
Based on the number of awkward encounters I've had
基于我早上在她公寓门口尴尬邂逅
with strange men leaving her apartment in the morning,
陌生过夜男士的数量
plus the number of times she's returned home wearing the same clothes
加上遇见她穿着前晚衣服
she wore the night before...
早上回家的次数
Okay, Sheldon, I think you've made your point.
好了  谢尔顿  我们都明白你意思了
So we multiply 193--
那就是193人
minus 21 men before the loss of virginity--
减去她失去童贞之前的21人
so 172 times 0.18 gives us...
即172人乘以0.18
30.96 sexual partners.
30.96位性伴侣
Let's round that up to 31.
约等于31
Okay, Sheldon, you are so wrong.
好了  谢尔顿  这根本不对
That is not even close to the real number.
跟实际数字大相径庭
I'm gonna need a drink over here.
这里给我来杯酒
This is very interesting.
这真有趣
Cultural perceptions are subjective.
个人的文化认知是非常主观的
Penny, to your mind, are you a slut?
佩妮  在你看来  你是荡妇吗
No! No!
不  不是
No.
不是
Let's just all finish our dinners, okay?
我们还是自顾自用餐好了  好吗
This is an interesting topic.
确实是个有趣的话题
How many sexual encounters have you had?
你有多少次性经验
Does volunteering for a scientific experiment
这要看志愿参加科学实验
in which orgasm was achieved by electronically
通过电子系统刺激人脑中的
stimulating the pleasure centers of the brain count?
愉悦中心区获得性高潮也算吗
I should think so.
我想应该算的
Then 128.
那就是128次
Okay, come on.
好的  进来吧
Almost there.
就快到了
- Don't tug. - No tugging.
-别用力拉  -我没在拉
Next time, take your own advice.
下回你自己搞定
Excuse me, could you help us out?
打扰下  能否帮帮我们
My, my, my.
天哪天哪天哪
What do we have here?
这怎么回事
I slipped and fell.
我不小心滑倒了
Yeah, we get that a lot.
嗯  这我们经常碰到
What is this?
这是什么
It's a robot arm.
是机器人的手臂
Where's the rest of the robot?
那机器人的其他部分呢
I only built the arm.
我就造了手臂
'Cause that's all you needed, right?
因为你就需要这个  是吗
Can you please just help me?!
能先帮我解决这再说吗
All right, all right.
好吧  好吧
Hang on, stay calm.
稍安勿躁
I need an orderly with a wheelchair.
请派护理员送轮椅来
I got a robot hand grasping a man's penis out here.
有被机械手钳住小弟弟的来看急诊
You think you could be a little more discreet?
你讲话就不能含蓄点
I'm sorry,we don't have a code for "Robot hand grasping a man's penis."
抱歉  "机械手钳住小弟弟"这种情况未设代码
Why is it hooked up to a computer?
它为何还连到电脑上
- Uh, it's what controls the arm. - But it's frozen.
-就是通过电脑控制机械手的  -但电脑死机了
Did you try turning it off and back on again?
你试过关机重启吗
No, you see, it's more complicated than that.
不  这事远比这复杂得多
No, wait!
别  住手
Winnie the Pooh is out of the honey tree.
小熊维尼终于从蜂蜜树中脱困
Now can we have cookies and Hawaiian Punch?
现在能让我们吃饼干和夏威夷宾治了吧
You were right.
你说得对
This was a very productive evening.
这个夜晚确实收获颇丰
I saw a whole new side of Amy Farrah Fowler tonight.
今晚我见识到了艾米·菲拉·福勒全新的一面
I did not have sex with 31 guys.
我没跟31个男人有过性关系
I'll be happy to check the math, but numbers don't lie, Penny.
我很乐意验算下  但数字不会骗人的
In any event, now that Amy and I have spent quality time together,
不管怎样  现在我和艾米已共度了"美好时光"
I feel much more confident
我就更有信心
proceeding to the next stage of our relationship.
继续将我俩关系发展到下一阶段了
And that is?
什么阶段
Using in vitro fertilization and a surrogate uterus
利用试管授精和代孕
to gift humanity with our progeny.
生下我们的后代向人类献礼
You're still on that?
你还在计划这个
In these uncertain times, doesn't humanity deserve a gift?
人世无常  人类难道不该有所安慰
Okay, you know what?
好吧  这样吧
I'm gonna come at this in a whole new way.
我再换种方式跟你说
Sheldon, if you try to make a baby with Amy in a petri dish,
谢尔顿  如果你想用培养皿造出你跟艾米的孩子
I'm gonna tell your mother on you.
我一定会去告诉你的妈妈
That's no threat.
这威胁不了我
My mother's always wanted a grandchild.
我妈一直都想抱孙子的
Really? Your deeply religious born-again Christian mother
真的  你那虔信基督再生的母亲
wants a test-tube grandbaby born out of wedlock?
会想要一个非婚生的试管婴儿当她的孙子
Curses.
诅咒你
If I'd thought of that in the first place,
我要是早点想出这招
I could've saved myself this whole night.
今晚也不用受这份罪了
Well, it's not that late.
现在还不算晚
You could still go out and look for number 32.
你还是可以出去寻找32号性伴侣
Good night.
晚安
Hey, Howard, what's up?
霍华德  怎么了
I've decided not to procreate.
我决定不要孩子了
Yeah, yeah, great.
好的  很好
Howard, uh, slow down.
霍华德  慢点说
What do you mean it happened again?
什么叫悲剧重演了